# Dikshit Hegde







Understanding how human brain perceives three-dimensional space is a challenging task. As a Research Fellow at Center of Excellence in Visual Intelligence under the guidance of Dr. Uma Mudenagudi and Ramesh Ashok Tabib, I have worked on Learning Representation of 2D/3D Data for better interpretation of Human like perception of 3D space.

#### Research Interest =

Unsupervised Learning | Geometric Learning | Learning Representation | Categorization | Incremental Learning

## Experience

CEVI | KLE Tech Research Fellow

06/2021 – Present Learning Representation of Data, Understanding the Geometry of 3D Data

Technical Consultant SFFD

10/2021 - 01/2023 Use of Annotated of Images and Support for building in-house tools

Software Engineer MulticoreWare

09/2020 - 05/2021 Human Pose Estimation (2D and 3D Pose)

MulticoreWare Project Intern

01/2020 - 08/2021 Human Activity Recognition, Ball Tracking

IIT Delhi Research Intern

06/2019 - 07/2019 Categorization of Image through Clustering towards better 3D Reconstruction

IIT Delhi Research Intern

06/2018 - 07/2018 Relocalization of a Query Image in 3D Generated Map

#### Education

2020 2016	Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication CGPA: 9.04/10   KLE Technological University, Hubballi, India
2016 2014	Pre-Education University Physics: 94/100 Math: 96/100   Vidyaniketan PU Science College, Hubbali, India
2014 2011	Secondary School Education  Marks: 548/625   Dr. G.V.J.R.E.M.H. School, Hubbali, India

### Skills

Python | C | PyTorch | Technical Writing | Linux | Presentation Skills

Pu	b	li	са	ti	O	n	S
	$\sim$		$\sim$	~1	$\mathbf{}$		$\boldsymbol{\smile}$

ICCVW (e-Heritage) 2023 DeFi: Detection and Filling of Holes in Point Clouds Towards Restoration of Digitized Cultural Heritage Models Ramesh Ashok Tabib, Dikshit Hegde, Tejas Anvekar, Uma Mudenagudi

CVPRW (StruCo3D) 2023 IPD-Net: SO(3) Invariant Primitive Decompositional Network for 3D Point Clouds

Ramesh Ashok Tabib, Nitishkumar Upasi, Tejas Anvekar, Dikshit Hegde, Uma Mudenagudi

SIGGRAPH Asia

Metric KNN is All You Need

2022

Tejas Anvekar, Ramesh Ashok Tabib, **Dikshit Hegde**, Uma Mudenagudi

CVPRW (IMW) 2022 DA-AE: Disparity-Alleviation Auto-Encoder Towards Categorization of Heritage Images for Aggrandized 3D Reconstruction

Dikshit Hegde, Tejas Anvekar, Ramesh Ashok Tabib, Uma Mudenagudi

CVPRW (DLGC) 2022 VG-VAE: A Venatus Geometry Point-Cloud Variational Autoencoder

Tejas Anvekar, Ramesh Ashok Tabib, Dikshit Hegde, Uma Mudenagudi

ICVGIP 2021 Modelling Nuisance Classifier Towards Class-Incremental Learning

of Crowd-sourced Data

Ramesh Ashok Tabib, T Santoshkumar, Dikshit Hegde, Adarsh Jamadandi, Uma Mudenagudi

CoCoNET (VisionNet)

2020

Deep Features for Categorization of Heritage Images Towards

3D Reconstruction

Ramesh Ashok Tabib, **Dikshit Hegde**, T Santoshkumar, Srikar HI, Mutturaj Harage,

Chaitra Desai, Ujwala Patil, Uma Mudenagudi

NCVPRIPG

Relocalization of Camera in a 3D Map on Memory Restricted

2020 Devices

Deepti Hegde, Dikshit Hegde, Ramesh Ashok Tabib, Uma Mudenagudi

#### Co-curricular Activities

CEVI | KLE Tech 2022 Resource Person at Summer School in Visual Intelligence

Introduction to Image Processing, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Computer vision

ATAL FDP

Resource Person at ATAL Faculty Development Program

2023 Research Challenges and A

Research Challenges and Application in Visual Intelligence (AICTE ATAL FDP) at KLE TU I CEVI

SEED

Resource Person at KLETU - SAMSUNG SEED Lab

2022

Introduction to Python and its application in AI/ML for Interns at SEED Lab I CEVI

CEVI | KLE Tech

Resource Person at CEVI

2021

Introduction to 2D/3D Human Pose Estimation and Application in Real-time.

SAMSUNG

Envoy for Industry Collaborative Project

2018-2019

SAMSUNG SRIB – KLE Technological University (SoECE)

#### Certifications -

CVIT | IIIT H 3D Vision Summer School

2022 Introduction to 3D data processing and its application.

IIT Madras Deep Learning

2018 (Online) Introduction to Deep Learning

CEVI | KLE Tech Summer School in Visual Intelligence

2017 Introduction to Image Processing, Machine Learning, Computer Vision and its application.

**Projects** 

DST - IHDS Pipeline for preserving the Heritage sites in digital format using

2018 - Present crowdsourced images (Sponsored)

Acquiring and processing of Images towards generation and presentation of 3D models

AICTE - RPS Shape Representation

2018 - 2021 Inference of classification on encrypted data.

SAMSUNG SRIB Data Encryption

2018 - 2019 Inference of classification on encrypted data.

Relocalization of an Agent in a known 3D SLAM Generated Map

2018 Localizing image in a know 3D map using orb features and K-Means.

MulticoreWare Human Activity Recognition

2020 Industry Internship at MulticoreWare

MulticoreWare Human Pose Estimation

2020-2021 Industry Project at MulticoreWare

MulticoreWare Ball Tracking in Sports

2020 Industry Internship at MulticoreWare

SIH | HCL Real-Time Multiple Person Recognition and Tracking for CCTV

2019 Cameras

HCL | Smart India Hackathon (Software Edition)

SEED Annotation Check Tool

2022 Collaborative with Student Ecosystem for Engineered Data (SEED)

SEED Annotate Me Tool

2022 Collaborative with Student Ecosystem for Engineered Data (SEED)

Declaration

I declare the above data is appropriate according to my knowledge.